College English Test, Band 4, Part 2, Listening, Comprehension
Section A, Directions
In this section, you will hear three news reports.
At the end of each news report, you will hear two or three questions.
Both the news report and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the centre.
News report 1
A Florida teenager and an Atlanta woman won the overall men's and women's divisions Saturday at the annual 7 mile bridge run.
Vaclav Berza, 15, of Big Pine Key, Florida, finished first overall.
He completed the race in 41 minutes and 1 second and claimed the top spot in the men's division.
Berza won third place in the 2022 race.
He is a student at Marathon High School.
Joanna Stevens, 28, of Atlanta, completed the course in 41 minutes and 12 seconds.
She won the women's division title and placed second overall.
The race drew competitors from 41 U.S. states.
There were also runners from other countries, including Canada, the UK and Switzerland.
The run closed the span between the middle and lower keys to traffic for three hours Saturday.
The April contest is one of the most popular running events in the southeastern United States.
The race field filled within minutes after online registration opened in January.
Questions 1 and 2 are based on the news report you have just heard.
Question 1. What does the news reports say about Vaclav Berza and Joanna Stevens?
Question 2. What do we learn about the April contest?
News report 2.
British astronaut Tim Peek is stepping down permanently from his role as a European astronaut.
He's going to take up a full-time position as ambassador for science and space instead.
Work he's been doing since 2019.
The former British Army Air Corps helicopter pilot was selected as a European Space Agency astronaut in 2009.
He flew to the space station for a six-month tour in 2015.
The tour saw him control a robot on Earth remotely from orbit.
He also helped dock to spacecraft.
Tim said, being an astronaut has been the most extraordinary experience.
I've had the privilege of working with an exceptional team of individuals during the past 13 years with the agency.
It has been incredibly exciting and rewarding.
By assuming the role of an ambassador for human flights to space,
I'll continue to support the European and the UK Space agencies.
Questions 3 and 4 are based on the news report you have just heard.
Question 3. What do we learn from the news report about Tim Peek?
About Tim Peek.
Question 4. What does Tim Peek say about his work with the European Space Agency?
The news report 3.
An ASDA store in Wales is now home to five cats after they wandered in and made themselves comfortable.
The supermarket is known for its loyal customers, but now has a different kind of visitor that has appeared over the last year.
Regular shoppers at the supermarket are familiar with the site of several cats, settling down in the shop aisles.
The unusual situation started about 12 months ago, when one cat routinely started visiting the store.
Local newspapers reported that puzzled customers posted on Facebook groups to try to find out if the cat was lost.
But its owner assured the concerned customers it was very much loved and fed at home.
It just enjoyed visiting the shop.
Staff did their best to discourage the pet from hanging around, but instead of leaving and never coming back, it invited its friends around.
There are now at least five different cats who come almost on a daily basis.
They visit the store so much that staff have been forced to put up signs, asking their customers not to feed them.
Questions 5-7 are based on the news reports you have just heard.
Question 5. What do we learn about the five cats seen in the ASDA store?
Question 6. What did some customers think when they saw the first cat routinely appear in the store?
Question 7. What are customers asked not to do?
Question 6. What do you think the next question is?
Question 8. What do you think the next question is?
Question 9. What does the man suggest the woman taken to consideration?
Question 10. What does the woman say she did during high school?
Question 11. What does the man say he'll do at the end of the conversation?
Question 12. What does the man say he'll do at the end of the conversation?
Question 12. What do you think the next question is?
Question 12. What is the woman doing?
Question 13. How does the man describe Bobo Man the action figure?
Question 14. What kind of game does the woman think would be good for Lawrence?
Question 15. What do we learn from the conversation about the game battleships?
Question 13. What do you think the next question is?
Question 12. What do you think the next question is?
They found four rules that motivate consumers to buy. When people want to make a quick and easy choice, when the product is complex, when it's difficult to compare alternatives and when consumers don't have clear preferences.
So as you can see, when it comes to choices, less is more.
Question 17. What did the psychologist want to find out in their 2012 study about J.M.'s?
Question 18. What is the finding of an extensive study published in 2015?
Question 18. What do you think the next question is?
Question 19. What do many Americans think of volunteering?
Question 20. How could companies ensure both employees and employers benefit from volunteering?
Question 21. What did 75% of employees say about volunteering in a survey?
Question 23. What do you think the next question is?
Question 21. What do you think the next question is?
Question 22. What do we learn about the UK's retail sector food waste?
Question 23. What do you think the next question is?
Question 24. What do you think the next question is?
Question 25. What do you think the next question is?
Question 25. Why will suppliers always have a certain amount of surplus?
That's the end of listening comprehension.