College English Test, Band 6, Part 2, Listening Comprehension
Section A, Directions
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices,
Marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the centre.
Conversation 1
We are down to two candidates for one position,
and we need to decide by the end of the day in order to finalise this whole procedure.
Yes, but it isn't an easy choice to make. Both applicants are quite strong.
Let's get to it then. Both of them went to good universities,
and both of them studied business-related subjects.
So academically, I'd say they're pretty much the same. What do you think?
I would agree, yes. The only difference worse noting perhaps,
is that it looks like Rachel scored moderately stronger grades throughout high school and university.
But as I said, only a tiny bit higher than Peter.
That's true, and worth noting, thank you.
In addition, Rachel interviewed very well.
I thought she came across as bright and alert.
Yes, she asked some very good questions about the position and the company,
which made me think she is very keen about the job.
I thought so too. Now let's look at Peter's interview performance.
I thought he also did very well.
He came across as respectful and professional, wouldn't you say?
Calm and poised. Very mature for his age.
Exactly. In my notes, I wrote that he seemed composed and in control of his emotions.
I think he definitely looked more mature than Rachel.
Interesting. So we agree that Rachel appeared inexperienced and less mature than Peter.
Even though both candidates are the same age and have practically no work experience.
When comparing them side by side, yes, Peter seems more self-assured somehow.
Maybe it was something about their body language.
Sure, maybe he was simply less nervous.
Maybe. Who knows? To be honest, I think I like Rachel better.
Hmm, really? I think I like Peter.
Well, if there's a tie and we can't come to an agreement, then we'll take it to John
and let him cast the deciding votes.
Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. Why does the man think it is difficult to make the decision?
Question 2. What do the speakers say may be worth noting?
Question 3. According to the man, what might account for Peter appearing somewhat more self-assured than Rachel?
Question 4. What does the man say they will do if they can't reach an agreement?
Conversation 2. We're here with Clementine Ortega, head designer of the private fashion label, Laurentge.
To discuss her latest collection, Ms. Ortega, how would you describe this season's look?
To be honest, my preferred style has always been on the ambiguous side, and I think this collection is even more so.
I try not to adhere to social norms and expectations.
Rather, I always try to incorporate something slightly absurd into my aesthetic.
The assortments of accessories in this collection have had quite the impact on critics.
The dazzling cape deployed at the end of the show, for example, bewildered many in the audience.
What was your inspiration for this piece?
Over the summer, I traveled through rural mountain villages throughout Asia, in search of handicrafts to decorate my new studio with.
The embroidery done by the women in a particular village was so exquisite, I couldn't stop thinking about it.
Trying to recreate their designs would have been futile, so instead I applied my own eccentric approach.
Using glitter, I drew similar intricate patterns onto the velvet cape.
This ended up in the glamorous luminous look that concluded the show.
It was indeed majestic, and yet there I say masculine at the same time.
Well, yes, that was intentional. I like to merge styles that are often at opposite ends of the fashion spectrum.
Hence, the sparkling cape was paired with a traditional power suit you would typically see in a business setting.
It was sensational if I do say so myself.
Spectacular for sure. A stunning show all around.
Going against stereotypes, the incorporation of indigenous aspects, along with your underlying signature touch,
made this collection a statement of the season.
You have proven yourself a formidable young designer, and we can't wait to see what creations you come up with next.
Questions 5-8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What are the speakers mainly talking about?
Question 6. What does the woman say she always tries to incorporate into her aesthetic?
Question 7. What does the woman say she likes to do?
Question 8. What is the man looking forward to?
Section B. Directions. In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the centre.
Passage 1. Pet dogs can often readily understand a wide range of their owner's commands and gestures.
But are these abilities inborn or are they exclusively learned through training?
To find out, a new study examined whether stray dogs could understand human gestures.
The study revealed that 80% of participating dogs successfully followed pointing gestures to a specific location.
Despite having never received prior training.
The results suggest that dogs can understand complex gestures by simply watching humans.
This could have implications in reducing conflict between stray dogs and humans.
Dogs were domesticated 10,000 to 15,000 years ago.
This means they are probably the oldest domesticated animals on the planet.
Humans then bred dogs with the most desirable and useful traits so that they could function as companions and workers.
This resulted in domesticated dogs that are highly responsive to human commands and gestures.
However, it was not clear whether dogs understand us through training alone or whether this was an inherent ability.
Why does this matter?
Stray dogs are a common feature in cities around the world.
They may observe and occasionally interact with people.
But such dogs have never been trained and are behaviourally wild.
Conflicts between stray dogs and humans are a problem.
Understanding how humans shape stray dogs' behaviour may help alleviate this problem.
According to the researchers of the new study, stray dogs are intelligent creatures.
They closely observe humans and use their understanding of us to make a decision.
Treating stray dogs with sensitivity and respect and giving them space the researchers assert can reduce much conflict.
Questions 9-11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9-What does the passage say about 80% of participating dogs in the new study?
Question 10-What may help alleviate the problem caused by stray dogs?
Question 11-What do the researchers suggest we do to reduce conflicts between stray dogs and humans?
Question 2- Think your refrigerator is just one big box of evenly cold air?
Not so. The temperature inside the average fridge actually varies from front to back, bottom to top and everywhere in between.
Because of this, food product placement within the appliance is far more important than you probably realise.
The whole purpose of the modern refrigerator is to slow the growth of bacteria which thrive in temperatures from 4.4 to 60 degrees Celsius.
As a result, refrigerators are typically set at or below that low end to protect foods against bacteria.
Although it might seem like time spent organising the fridge will spoil your day, doing so will actually make it more user friendly, easier to clean and food safety conscious.
Those little bins on the inside of refrigerator doors are convenient, but they don't maintain a consistent temperature, so definitely refrain from putting perishable foods in there.
The top area is not as cold as the bottom of the fridge, so save it for the foods that don't need extra chilly temperatures.
Store foods that are ready to eat or already cooked on the top shelf.
The middle shelf is the most temperature controlled part of the fridge, so place eggs here.
Drinks and prepared foods can also live on the middle shelf if you run out of room up top.
The back of the bottom shelf is the coldest spot in the fridge, so store perishable dairy products here to keep them edible longer.
Never store foods with high water content here because the water within them can and will freeze, effectively ruining them.
Questions 12 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 12. Why is food product placement within the fridge very important?
Question 13. What does the passage say is the whole purpose of the modern refrigerator?
Question 14. Where in the fridge should we store foods already cooked?
Question 15. Why should we never store foods with high water content at the back of the bottom shelf?
Question 14. What is the whole purpose of the modern refrigerator?
Question 13. What is the whole purpose of the modern refrigerator?
Question 17. What does the speaker think excites her most about her research?
Question 18. How does the speaker approach her research project?
Question 18. What is the whole purpose of the modern refrigerator?
Question 18. What does the speaker say about most colleges and graduate schools in America?
Question 20. How do students at the Culinary Institute of America view mise en place or put in place?
Question 21. What does the speaker advise us to do at the end of the talk?
Question 23. Why do we stop making goals for ourselves and stop progressing in life?
Question 23. What is the whole purpose of the modern refrigerator?
It is so simple yet has an immediate positive impact on our thinking.
Question 23. What do people tend to do when they have reached midlife?
Question 24. Why do we find ourselves irritated for not achieving the goal?
Question 25. What does the speaker say has an immediate positive impact on our thinking?
That is the end of listening comprehension.